<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<part xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.0" xml:id="overview">
    <title>LinkRest Overview</title>
 
    <chapter xml:id="overview-what-is-linkrest">
        <title>What is LinkRest</title>
        <para>LinkRest is a set of tools to build web APIs for your data. You would use it to expose
            a data store (such as a relational database) as a RESTful web service. To achieve that
            goal LinkRest defines a simple HTTP/JSON-based protocol (described in <xref
                linkend="protocol"/>) and a server-side framework (described in <xref
                linkend="framework"/>). The protocol ensures that any client, be it JavaScript, a mobile
            app or maybe a server-side app, can make sense of any LinkRest-enabled service. The
            framework is written in Java and helps you to build services adhering to the
            protocol.</para>
        <para>LinkRest is open source and is distributed under the terms of <link
                xlink:href="https://github.com/nhl/link-rest/blob/master/LICENSE.txt">BSD
                license</link>
        </para>
       
    </chapter>
    <chapter xml:id="overview-what-linkrest-is-not">
        <title>What LinkRest is Not</title>
        <para>LinkRest is not an automated engine to take your DB online with a single command. You
            still have to write code for JAX-RS endpoints (however simple and trivial that code
            might end up being). Having this code around allows you to customize processing,
            implement security around endpoints, hide certain methods, etc. This is a defensive
            approach that goes a long way to avoid unintended consequences when opening up your data
            on the web.</para>
        <para>Having said that, such an engine can be written on top of LinkRest with relative
            ease.</para>
        
    </chapter>
    <chapter xml:id="data-stores">
        <title>Supported Data Stores</title>
        <para>LinkRest is written on top of <link xlink:href="http://cayenne.apache.org">Apache
                Cayenne ORM</link> and supports any relational data store, such as MySQL or Oracle.
            Support for alternative data stores can be provided with relative ease. E.g. NoSQL
            databases, flat files, etc. E.g. we've written POJO and LDAP backends.</para>
        
    </chapter>
    
    <chapter xml:id="security-features">
        <title>Security</title>
        <para>From the very beginning LinkRest was designed with security in mind. It can be easily
            integrated with common web and enterprise security solutions (OAuth, <link
                xlink:href="http://shiro.apache.org/">Apache Shiro</link>, Spring Security, etc.),
            giving Java developers a straightforward API to implement custom object and
            attribute-level access. </para>
        
    </chapter>
</part>
